Chapter 131. The Peekquad meets the delight.
The intense Peekquad sailed on, the rolling waves and days went by. The
lifebo coffin still lightly swung, and another ship most miserably misnamed the
delight was described. As she drew nigh, all eyes were fixed upon her broad beams
called shears, which in some wailing ships crossed the quarter deck at the
height of 8 or 9 ft, serving to carry the spare, unrigged, or disabled boats.
Upon the stranger's shears were beheld the shattered white ribs and some few
splintered planks of what had once been a whaleboat, but you now saw through
this wreck as plainly as you see through the peeled, half unhinged and bleaching
skeleton of a horse.
Hast seen the white whale.
Look, replied the hollow cheicked captain from his taffrail, and with his
trumpet he pointed to the wreck. has killed him. "The harpoon is not yet
forged that will ever do that," answered the other, sadly glancing upon a rounded
hammock on the deck, whose gathered sides some noiseless sailors were busy
in sewing together. "Not forged!" And snatching Perth's leveled iron from the
crotch, Ahab held it out, exclaiming, "Look in, Antuer. Here in this hand I
hold his death. Tempered in blood and tempered by lightning are these barbs.
And I swear to temper them triply in that hot place behind the fin where the
white whale most feels his a cursed life.
Then God keep thee, old man. Seeest thou that? Pointing to the hammock. I bury
but one of five stout men who were alive only yesterday but were dead air night.
Only that one I bury. The rest were buried before they died. You sail upon their tomb.
Then turning to his crew. Are you ready there? Place the plank then on the rail
and lift the body. So then, oh God, advancing toward the hammock with
uplifted hands, may the resurrection and the life brace forward uphelm, cried
Ahab like lightning to his men.
But the suddenly started Peekquad was not quick enough to escape the sound of
the splash that the corpse soon made as it struck the sea. Not so quick indeed,
but that some of the flying bubbles might have sprinkled her hull with their ghostly baptism.
As Ahab now glided from the dejected delight, the strange life boy hanging at
the Peekquad stern came into conspicuous relief. "Ha! Yonder! Look yonder, men!"
cried a foreboing voice in her wake. "In vain, oh ye strangers! You fly our sad
burial! You but turn us your tap rail to show us your coffin.